Mohsen Saeidi

Senior Software Engineer

🔀 saeidi.mhsn@gmail.com

k https://mohsensaeidi.ir/



09/2011 - 08/2015 | Tehran, Iran

09/2007 - 08/2011 | Tehran, Iran

Professional Summary

Versatile software engineer experienced with the full software development life cycle and comfortable working within agile development frameworks. Organized and hardworking team player with strong verbal and written communication skills. Ready to bring many years of related experience to a challenging position.

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Hoffmann group	07/2021 – present Munich, Germany
Senior Software Engineer, Code It Labs	03/2020 – 06/2021 Munich, Germany
Technical Lead, Dotin	06/2017 – 01/2020 Tehran, Iran
Senior Software Engineer, Limoome	07/2016 - 05/2017 Tehran, Iran
Software Engineer, Fanap	07/2013 - 06/2016 Tehran, Iran
Junior Software Engineer, Karnik System	08/2012 - 06/2013 Tehran, Iran
Education	
Master of Science in Computer Networks,	09/2016 - 06/2019 Tehran, Iran

Sharif University of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology,

University of Tehran

Diploma in Physics and Mathematics discipline, Hatef High School

atef High School

Skills

Core Java Experience	• • • •	System Design & Architecture	• • • • •
Automating Unit Testing	• • • •	Software Development Life Cycle	• • • • •
Spring/Hibernate Frameworks	• • • •	Database Design	• • • • •
Bug Tracking, Troubleshooting	• • • •	Agile Development Methodology	• • • • •
Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL	• • • •	Problem-Solving Ability	• • • • •
Code Review	• • • •	Build Pipelines	• • • • •
Planning & Implementation	• • • •	New Employee Mentoring	• • • • •
CI & CD	• • • •	Micro Service Architecture	• • • • •
Docker & Kubernetes	• • • •	DevOps Principles	• • • • •
Event Driven Architecture	• • • •	Linux Administration	• • • • •
NoSQL DB	• • • •	C, C++, Python, C#	• • • • •
Big Data & Cloud Computing	• • • • •	Frontend Technologies	• • • • •

Languages

English	• • • •	German	• • • • •
Persian	• • • •	Arabic	• • • • •

Certificates And Awards

- SAP Certified Development Professional SAP Commerce Cloud 1905 Developer issued by SAP SE(2020) ☑
- Stack Overflow high reputation ☑

- 16th position among 20,000 participants in Iran university entrance MSc exam of Computer Engineering(2016)
- 2nd position in Iran RoboCup 2D Soccer Simulation competitions(2009)

Notable Projects

Hoffmann group 🛮

Hoffmann Group is active in the trade and manufacture of tools, factory equipment, and personal protective equipment and offers the associated consulting and services.

- **Technologies**: SAP Hybris Commerce 2011, Java11, Spring framework, Jenkins, Microservices, Docker, Apache Tomcat, PIM, JSP/Javascript, MySQL database, Ant/Maven, REST and SOAP service, Bitbucket.
- **Duties**: As a senior software engineer who works in scrum methodology, the major duties are: mentoring new team members, code review, developing new features, observing operations and tackling difficult problems.

Manor 🛮

Manor is a Swiss department store chain with its headquarters in Basel. It is Switzerland's largest department-store chain

- **Technologies**: SAP Hybris Commerce 1905, Java11, Spring framework, JSP, MySQL database, Maven/Gradle, Splunk, REST and SOAP service, Git.
- **Duties**: As an SAP Commerce developer my major duties are mapping client business requirements, processes, and objectives and then developing necessary modules.

Dotin Core Insurance

A general insurance system solution web enterprise that consists of many modules such as insurance setup, servicing, quotation, financial and accounting, claim processing, and recovery.

- **Technologies**: J2EE, CAS/SSO, Spring framework, Hibernate, Servlets/JSP, JSF, Oracle database, Tomcat, RabbitMQ, Redis, Maven, SOAP, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Git, and lots more.
- **Duties**: Java technical lead. My major duties were leading in software design, securing the quality of team deliverables, Implementing the best practices, and coding standards of the project, and also code review and mentoring team members.

Limoome 2

Limomi exports unique diets for different age groups by using the science of temperament and modern therapeutic diet.

• **Technologies**: Java, Spring boot, Hibernate/JPA, PostgreSQL, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Spring MVC, AWS, Heroku, Office 365, Git.

Recommendation System Based on Network Coding

My Master's Project which using network coding algorithms to improve the performance of map-reduce frameworks and implemented recommendation systems.

• Technologies: Hadoop, Spark, Java, Python, AWS, Star Cluster